Guide to the EDSource Records M1903
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Adminstration & Accountability
  - Administrators - School Leadership & Achievement; includes research/commission reports, books, articles, 1996-2009; 9.0 folder(s) (Box 62, Folders 1-9)
  - Administrators - School Leadership & Achievement; includes research/commission reports, books, articles, 1996-2009; 7.0 folder(s) (Box 63, Folders 1-7)
  - Teachers; preparation & development, standards, credentialing, mentoring, recruitment & retention, compensation, labor unions, collective bargaining; includes research/commission/policy reports, newsletters, articles, correspondence, notes, 1993-2011; 25.0 folder(s) (Carton 64, Folders 1-25)
  - Teachers; preparation & development, standards, credentialing, mentoring, recruitment & retention, compensation, labor unions, collective bargaining; includes research/commission/policy reports, newsletters, articles, correspondence, notes, 1993-2011; 37.0 folder(s) (Carton 65, Folders 1-37)
  - Accountability - Public School Accountability Act (PSAA); includes research/commission reports, committee meetings, articles, 1999-2006; 12.0 folder(s) (Carton 66, Folders 1-12)
  - Accountability - General; includes research/commission/forum/policy reports, newsletters, articles, 1996-2003; 15.0 folder(s) (Carton 66, Folders 13-27)
- Policy & Governance
  - Federal Policy; No Child Left Behind (NCLB), Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA), Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA), Improving America's Schools Act (IASA), Title I; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, legislation, articles, resources, correspondence, notes, 1987-2007; 23.0 folder(s) (Carton 67, Folders 1-23)
  - Governance; CA state & local government, school boards, administration/leadership, district organization, restructuring; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, legislation, articles, resources, correspondence, 1976-2005; 25.0 folder(s) (Carton 68, Folders 1-25)
  - Voting & Elections; titles and summaries of initiative measure/initiative constitution amendments; includes news releases & articles, correspondence, notes, 1991-2002; 6.0 folder(s) (Box 69, Folders 1-6)
  - School Vouchers; includes research/commission/policy reports, legislation, articles, 1989-2004; 5.0 folder(s) (Box 70, Folders 1-5)
  - School Vouchers; includes research/commission/policy reports, legislation, articles, 1989-2004; 10.0 folder(s) (Box 71, Folders 1-10)
- School Finance
  - School Finance - General; budget acts, development, reforms, property tax, equity, adequacy, state & local budget/finance, standards, accounting, resource allocation/distribution, CA Constitution Revision Commission, Williams v. CA; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, legislation, committee meetings, statistics, articles, correspondence, 1979-2009; 17.0 folder(s) (Carton 72, Folders 1-17)
  - School Finance - General; budget acts, development, reforms, property tax, equity, adequacy, state & local budget/finance, standards, accounting, resource allocation/distribution, CA Constitution Revision Commission, Williams v. CA; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, legislation, committee meetings, statistics, articles, correspondence, 1979-2009; 30.0 folder(s) (Carton 73, Folders 1-30)
  - School Finance - District Budgets; budget development, training, fiscal crisis management, Standard Account Code Structure (SACS); includes research/commission/policy reports, district budgets, articles, correspondence, notes, 1988-2005; 17.0 folder(s) (Carton 74, Folders 1-17)
  - School Finance - Adequacy; equalizing funding, generating/managing available resources; includes research/commission/policy reports, statistics, surveys, articles, correspondence, notes, 1997-2003; 8.0 folder(s) (Carton 74, Folders 18-25)
  - School Finance - Facilities; classroom design, construction, accessibility, energy needs, fund distribution, technology supply, computers; includes research/commission/policy reports, statistics, legislation, drafts, articles, correspondence, notes, 1986-2003; 18.0 folder(s) (Carton 75, Folders 1-18)
  - School Finance - Categorical Funding; deregulation of federal funding, flexibility; includes research/commission/policy reports, 1993-2004; 3.0 folder(s) (Carton 75, Folders 19-21)
  - School Finance - Lottery (1991); CA Lottery Act, revenue, fund allocation; includes research/commission/policy reports, legislation, drafts, articles, correspondence, notes, 1984-2000; 8.0 folder(s) (Carton 75, Folders 22-29)
  - School Finance - State Finance; state budgets, taxes, revenue; includes research/commission/policy reports, legislation, articles, 1997-2004; 5.0 folder(s) (Carton 75, Folders 30-34)
  - School Finance - Selected Readings; categorical aid, budgets, how CA compares, proposition 98, efficiency & adequacy, facilities, teacher compensation, academic standards, reforms; includes research/commission/legislative reports, 1999-2006; 7.0 folder(s) (Box 76, Folders 1-7)
  - School Finance - Selected Readings; categorical aid, budgets, how CA compares, proposition 98, efficiency & adequacy, facilities, teacher compensation, academic standards, reforms; includes research/commission/legislative reports, 2006-2011; 5.0 folder(s) (Box 77, Folders 1-5)
  - School Finance - Comparative Costs; comparative costs project, district rankings, class size, salaries, benefits; includes research/commission/data reports, proposals, drafts, statistics, advisory/committee meetings, correspondence, articles, notes, 1987-1993; 32.0 folder(s) (Carton 78, Folders 1-32)
  - School Finance - Comparative Costs; comparative costs project, district rankings, public & private/independent schools, class size, salaries, benefits; includes research/commission/data reports, proposals, drafts, statistics, advisory/committee meetings, correspondence, articles, notes, 1987-1993; 12.0 folder(s) (Box 79, Folders 1-12)
  - School Finance - Comparative Costs; Comparative Costs 1990: A Guide for Decision Making in California School Districts; includes research/data reports, statistics, 11.0 folder(s) (Carton 80, Folders 1-11)
  - School Finance - Fiscal Management; "Fiscal Management Training Needs of CA Local Agencies", fiscal policy; includes research/commission reports, committee meetings, correspondence, notes, 1986-1987; 5.0 folder(s) (Box 81, Folders 1-5)
  - School Finance - Revenue Limits; includes data reports, statistics, correspondence, notes, 1973-1983; 8.0 folder(s) (Box 82, Folders 1-8)
- Publication Files
  - Information Service Packets (1980-1987); publication series covering various topics: funding, budgets, education and workforce, ballot measures, bilingual education, special education, demographics, school facilities, testing, legislation; includes reports, topic papers, evaluations, flyers, resource cards, memorandums, correspondence, distribution lists, 48.0 folder(s) (Carton 83, Folders 1-48)
  - Information Service Packets (1987-1993); publication series covering various topics: funding, budgets, education and workforce, ballot measures, bilingual education, special education, demographics, school facilities, testing, legislation; includes reports, topic papers, evaluations, flyers, resource cards, memorandums, correspondence, distribution lists, 46.0 folder(s) (Carton 84, Folders 1-46)
  - Information Service Packets (1993-1997); publication series covering various topics: funding, budgets, education and workforce, ballot measures, bilingual education, special education, demographics, school facilities, testing, legislation; includes reports, topic papers, evaluations, flyers, resource cards, memorandums, correspondence, distribution lists, 33.0 folder(s) (Carton 85, Folders 1-33)
  - Information Service Packets (1997-2001); publication series covering various topics: funding, budgets, education and workforce, ballot measures, bilingual education, special education, demographics, school facilities, testing, legislation; includes reports, topic papers, evaluations, flyers, resource cards, memorandums, correspondence, distribution lists, 37.0 folder(s) (Carton 86, Folders 1-37)
  - Information Service Packets (2001-2006); publication series covering various topics: funding, budgets, education and workforce, ballot measures, bilingual education, special education, demographics, school facilities, testing, legislation; includes reports, topic papers, evaluations, flyers, resource cards, memorandums, correspondence, distribution lists, 45.0 folder(s) (Carton 87, Folders 1-45)
  - Information Service Surveys, 2006-2008; 2.0 folder(s) (Box 88, Folders 1-2)
  - Resource Cards raw data (2002-2004); information covering various topics: school facilities, class size, student demographics, test scores, standardized testing, graduation/dropout rates, bilingual education, special education, charter schools, legislation, elections, collective bargaining, teacher demographics, teacher requirements, recruitment & retention, school revenue, budgets, financing; includes drafts, notes, correspondence, 69.0 folder(s) (Carton 89, Folders 1-69)
  - Resource Cards raw data (2005-2006); information covering various topics: school facilities, class size, student demographics, test scores, standardized testing, graduation/dropout rates, bilingual education, special education, charter schools, legislation, elections, collective bargaining, teacher demographics, teacher requirements, recruitment & retention, school revenue, budgets, financing; includes drafts, notes, correspondence, 83.0 folder(s) (Carton 90, Folders 1-83)
  - Resource Cards raw data (2007-2008); information covering various topics: school facilities, class size, student demographics, test scores, standardized testing, graduation/dropout rates, bilingual education, special education, charter schools, legislation, elections, collective bargaining, teacher demographics, teacher requirements, recruitment & retention, school revenue, budgets, financing; includes drafts, notes, correspondence, 86.0 folder(s) (Carton 91, Folders 1-86)
  - Resource Cards (published)(2001-2006); information covering various topics: school facilities, class size, student demographics, test scores, standardized testing, graduation/dropout rates, bilingual education, special education, charter schools, legislation, elections, collective bargaining, teacher demographics, teacher requirements, recruitment & retention, school revenue, budgets, financing, 6.0 folder(s) (Box 92, Folders 1-6)
  - Resource Cards (published)(2007-2011); information covering various topics: school facilities, class size, student demographics, test scores, standardized testing, graduation/dropout rates, bilingual education, special education, charter schools, legislation, elections, collective bargaining, teacher demographics, teacher requirements, recruitment & retention, school revenue, budgets, financing, 5.0 folder(s) (Box 93, Folders 1-5)
  - School Services of California Reports; budgets/funding/financing, legislation, class size, districts, special education, charter/private schools, standards, performance, testing, reforms, teacher credentialing/evaluation/compensation, facilities; includes reports, correspondence, 2000-2001; 40.0 folder(s) (Carton 94, Folders 1-40)
  - Publication Files - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, surveys, meetings, legislation, drafts, correspondence, articles, notes, 1986-2000; 23.0 folder(s) (Carton 95, Folders 1-23)
  - Publication Files - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, surveys, meetings, legislation, drafts, correspondence, articles, notes, 1981-2001; 20.0 folder(s) (Carton 96, Folders 1-20)
  - Publication Files - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, surveys, meetings, legislation, drafts, correspondence, articles, notes, 1992-2000; 21.0 folder(s) (Carton 97, Folders 1-21)
  - Publication Files - School Finance - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, budgets, graphs, meetings, legislation, drafts, correspondence, articles, notes, 1985-1999; 23.0 folder(s) (Carton 98, Folders 1-23)
  - Publication Files - School Finance - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, budgets, graphs, meetings, legislation, drafts, correspondence, articles, notes, 1985-1999; 11.0 folder(s) (Carton 99, Folders 1-11)
  - Publication Files - Governor's Budget - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, budgets, legislation, correspondence, articles, notes, 1986-2002; 12.0 folder(s) (Carton 99, Folders 12-23)
  - Publication Files - Governor's Budget - research/files for EdSource publications; includes research/commission/policy/data reports, statistics, budgets, legislation, correspondence, articles, notes, 2002-2004; 3.0 folder(s) (Box 100, Folders 1-3)
- Organization Files
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1978-1994; 53.0 folder(s) (Carton 103, Folders 1-53)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1981-2004; 26.0 folder(s) (Carton 104, Folders 1-26)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1980-2005; 7.0 folder(s) (Box 105, Folders 1-7)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1980-2005; 5.0 folder(s) (Box 106, Folders 1-5)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1986-2011; 29.0 folder(s) (Carton 107, Folders 1-29)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1979-2011; 39.0 folder(s) (Carton 108, Folders 1-39)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports; includes applications, proposals, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1979-2008; 39.0 folder(s) (Carton 109, Folders 1-39)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports - Hewlett; includes applications, proposals, interim reports/updates, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 2000-2011; 23.0 folder(s) (Carton 110, Folders 1-23)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports - Irvine Foundation; includes applications, proposals, interim reports/updates, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1980-2008; 34.0 folder(s) (Carton 111, Folders 1-34)
  - Fund Development - Grant Proposals/Reports - Stuart Foundation; includes applications, proposals, interim reports/updates, drafts, budgets, research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1985-2007; 20.0 folder(s) (Carton 112, Folders 1-20)
  - Fund Development - Forums; includes forum funder reports, project evaluation summaries, proposals, attendee lists, commission/research reports, budgets, articles, correspondence, notes, 14.0 folder(s) (Carton 112, Folders 21-34)
  - Fund Development - Corporate Solicitation; includes applications, project reports/summaries, correspondence, notes, 1997-2002; 6.0 folder(s) (Box 113, Folders 1-6)
  - Fund Development - Education First Consulting (EFC); includes research reports, drafts, 2010; 3.0 folder(s) (Box 113, Folders 7-9)
  - Board of Directors Files (1977-1986); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 35.0 folder(s) (Carton 114, Folders 1-35)
  - Board of Directors Files (1978-1991); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 42.0 folder(s) (Carton 115, Folders 1-42)
  - Board of Directors Files (1989-1995); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 32.0 folder(s) (Carton 116, Folders 1-32)
  - Board of Directors Files (1992-2004); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 41.0 folder(s) (Carton 117, Folders 1-41)
  - Board of Directors Files (2002-2006); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 6.0 folder(s) (Box 118, Folders 1-6)
  - Board of Directors Files (2002-2008); includes committee meetings reports/minutes, agendas, member lists, by-laws, orientation information, event information, financial reports, budget information, drafts, correspondence, notes, 3.0 folder(s) (Box 119, Folders 1-3)
  - Staff Journals; includes chronological notes, 1977-2003; 26.0 folder(s) (Carton 120, Folders 1-26)
  - Website - Ed Data; national comparison, Standard Accounting Code Structure (SACS), Academic Performance Index (API); includes research/commission/data reports, statistics, meetings, articles, correspondence, notes, 1995-2008; 12.0 folder(s) (Carton 101, Folders 1-12)
  - Website - General; organization, site navigation, search engine, testing, maintenance, data bases, e-commerce; includes research, surveys, meetings, correspondence, articles, notes, 1998-2001; 39.0 folder(s) (Carton 102, Folders 1-39)
  - Organization History; historical formation and development, California Coalition for Fair School Finance, League of Women Voters of California, California Congress of Parents & Teachers, California Division of American Association of University Women, EdSource; includes research/commission/policy/financial reports, board of directors lists, by-laws, meetings, events, budget information, organization publications, drafts, surveys, resource cards, correspondence, notes, articles, 1976-1998; 33.0 folder(s) (Carton 121, Folders 1-33)
  - Organization History; historical formation and development, California Coalition for Fair School Finance, League of Women Voters of California, California Congress of Parents & Teachers, California Division of American Association of University Women, EdSource; includes research/commission/policy/financial reports, board of directors lists, by-laws, meetings, events, budget information, organization publications, drafts, surveys, resource cards, correspondence, notes, articles, 1998-2011; 30.0 folder(s) (Carton 122, Folders 1-30)
- Media
  - Photographs & Negatives; anniversaries, conferences, legislative reception, events (holidays), board meetings, staff & office, history display; includes photographs, negatives, notes, 1987-1998; 11.0 folder(s) (Box 123, Folders 1-11)
  - Computer Files & Miscellaneous Media; "Similar Students, Different Results", private schools, charter schools, English Learners, educational reforms, publications, data, meetings, 1992-2007; 19.0 Item(s) (2)folders, (8)compact discs, (6)3 1/2 inch floppy disks, (1)5 1/4 floppy disk, (3)audio-cassettes (Box 124, Items 19)
  - Computer Files; publications, data, 1989-2005; 32.0 Item(s) (1)folder, (31)zip floppy disks (Box 125, Items 32)
  - Computer Files; publications, data, 1989-2005; 52.0 Item(s) (5)zip floppy disks, (10)3 1/2 inch floppy disks, (37)compact discs (Box 126, Items 52)
  - Video Media; includes school funding/finance, academic standards, 1987-2007; 12.0 videotape(s) (Box 127, Videotapes 12)
  - Video Media; includes academic standards, Standard Account Code Structure (SACS), performance, conferences/events, 1997-2004; 12.0 videotape(s) (Box 128, Videotapes 12)
  - Video Media; includes state senate programs, demographics, leadership, 1987-2004; 10.0 videotape(s) (Box 129, Videotapes 10)
  - Video Media; includes public schools, violence in schools, school choice, news reports/documentaries, 1991-2001; 11.0 videotape(s) (Box 130, Videotapes 11)
  - Video Media; includes achievement, news reports/documentaries, 1993-2000; 6.0 videotape(s) (Box 131, Videotapes 6)
  - Digital Media; includes news reports/documentaries, achievement, EdSource 30th anniversary, academic standards, funding/finance, district data, 1990-2007; 28.0 Item(s) [28 digital-video-discs & compact-discs] (Box 132, Items 28)